hi there in this second video of the
series what is the Magellan course I
want to talk about some distinctions
that we set up in the first video and
those are the distinctions between what
we might term post-modernism and post
post modernism whereas I have it here a
post poem in these things these
distinctions are valuable not so much in
terms of the content that the magellan
course is most interested in but in
terms of the trajectory away from the
types of thinking being and learning and
action logics that are currently either
being utilized for being moved on to
from what the Magellan course is most
interested in and so in terms of the
first video we talked about a frontier
and everything we're going to talk about
today is on the near side of that
frontier so these will be distinctions
that are set up to help us understand
what the Magellan course is trying to
move beyond so we're trying to move even
beyond post post-modernism or postpone
well
okay
so if we look at what you make a grid of
some of these distinctions and what I
want to do here is say that this is the
post post modern version of different
aspects that we're going to look at this
would be the post modern version we will
look at the post modern version as a
reaction against what came before so
this would be what it's reacting to in
many cases that's the modern version but
we want to highlight that the post
modern is in many respects a reaction
against what came before so those are
some of the ways we're going to set this
up the post modern to the post
postmodern is not so much a reaction but
in general there's this process of
building on some of the value of the
post modern into a new integrative
post-postmodern so I just want to
highlight that in general the post
modern was a reaction is reactionary
against the previous forms and the post
post modern movement is more integrative
so that is a first distinction we can
make the post modern was in general
reactive whereas the post post mal tends
to be more concentrate and
integration so you hear words as
transcendence include the postmodern
whereas the modern is the postmodern is
trying to make more of an actual reacted
break against what has come before and
so people like gentlemen will say that
the postmodern has overstated the
reaction and the post-postmodern is now
trying to be synthetic to reclaim some
of what has gone before so that's a
first distinction the other categories
that I want to look at is a category we
could call what's the different views
the overall view that these different
mindsets but operating from Emily I
would say that the post homo view as
many of you will not be surprised this
perspectival so culminating with Ken
Wilber we've been able to actually
identify in that the perspectives from
which all these different views and
methodologies are arising in these
perspectives this mapping of this
perspectival domains isn't attempt to be
integrative and in synthetic so this
move build on the post post Mott the
postmodern view which was relatively
that there were many views and they were
all relative to each other in the way
the integrative or synthetic move and
postpone Oh built on that the saying yes
there
they're all relatively but they can be
contextualized by this map of
perspectives this relative aspect we can
see was a reaction against absolutism so
prior to the understanding that views
our perspectival which accounts for the
fact that there seem to be relative is a
reaction against the fact that opinions
and knowledge --is and worldviews are
not absolutely real for all trains and
so perspectival is a map of the we could
say the frames of reference and you see
this in science as well as in the
humanities this brings up to the domain
let's say I will call it just the domain
of knowledge and we want to look at the
post pomo or the most recent
understanding or approach to knowledge
and in general the the treatment of the
knowledge domain is through what we
might call on junctions or methodologies
and this relates to perspectival so
different injunctions will elicit
different perspective of frames
different methodologies will elicit
different types of evidence or data the
move then the synthetic move then into
here would be to be transdisciplinary
through the methods or injunction so we
have methodological pluralism Intel
methodological pluralism that's we see
that recent approach this methodological
pluralism was built on the notion of a
hermeneutic circle and shared discourse
that emerged during the postmodern term
and that was a reaction against a pretty
strict empiricism we can then look at
what we might call well how do the
different views receive or find meaning
in the modern age the general way to
find meaning was to assume that it was
discoverable that it was out there as
something ontologically real as
something constant in nature as
something an absolute an empirically
real and it could be discovered as a
reaction against that the postmodern
said modern movement of meaning as being
invincible
so you weren't so much discovering
meaning as inventing it with different
methodologies by taking on different
perspectives and frames not only was
inventive also we have this kind that's
of being constructed that meaning is
constructed when that gets incorporated
to this concept of taking on different
perspectives being
methodological II pluralistic being
synthetic and interpretive then the turn
it from postmodern to an or recent
understanding is that meaning is
actionable and so you start to see words
such like enactment an enactment Theory
an enactment unfolds all these concepts
these integrated concepts so that you
enact meaning through different
injunctions for example so that would be
another move between these three
different views this has been also
related to what a lot of people talk
about is that in the postmodern era
meaning was all about the context prior
to that it was all about the content as
if the content was just out there to be
discovered and building on that we have
that meaning is context independence
according to grades or hierarchies
there's some search to create a grading
system or a model or methodology of
grading context and that grading system
is copy itself considered context
independent when we look at the
aptitudes
that are important in these views
we see that in post-postmodern
the aptitude that's most important is
therefore not a theory because meta
theory is the attitude that generates
these supposed or sumed
or the goal is to be context independent
models of content and context that meta
fairy bill has been built on mediated
discourse and what I mean by mediated
discourse is discourse critical inquiry
in this course that has been mediated to
uncover the context dependency of
certain opinions or data or
understandings so mediated discourse was
much more related just to her or
minutest and building on that there's
this understanding that meta theory not
only mediates discourse but can come up
with ways to grade in ether not
hierarchical or some kind of graded
grading system where the context and the
content become themselves contextualize
the context itself becomes
contextualized through this contact
independent meta theory and the mediated
discourse was a reaction to just really
using senses so empiricism for example
relied heavily on observational
techniques that themselves were
developed through technology this is
very closely related then what do we
rely on to explain the knowledge or our
view and in this sense I'll just come
across here because it ties in very
closely is in this area it was
perception just our perception
categories our observations are hearing
our sight and the reaction to that there
was a focus on language and building on
those two the synthetic or integrative
need move is to look at patterns
patterns of both language and perception
if we look at what kind of process
dynamics are most in play we find that
in the most recent area what we'll
calling postponed oh we primarily see
developmental processes developmental
these patterns almost are entirely
developmental and these meta theories
almost entirely draw on developmental
hierarchies this has been built on the
previous
relational processes for sliding
contacts people like to say and that was
a reaction to primarily a mechanical or
mechanistic process mentality if we look
at the domain of inquiry that was the
focus in the in most of these views then
we find that we are entering in the
postponed pomo realm or view in create
the scale of the planet and the planet
itself has become an object of discourse
so prior to the post one and the pieces
of the planet were looked at Ecology's
geography societies geological
biophysical species but with the post
post one and we see that the planet
itself is being is construed as a monad
or an agenting monad the word gaia
brings up to mind or an organism so it
is a very recent that it's been able to
be actually the scale at which the
inquiry is happening this has been built
on the postmodern domain of inquiries
primarily culture and that was
reaction to basically just looking at
nature and thinking that people and
cultures were identical to natural
systems or physical physical nature
nature has a physical system productive
system so these are the primary
distinctions we can make in terms of
watching the movement or the journey
from the modern era and how the
postmodern reaction to the modern era
derive a different set of views in how
the post pomo
or the integrative or integral or
synthetic era built on what what has
been happening both the action and the
reaction into a more interpretive view
and just down here to make to expand
this into ethics and morality so we
could say that in terms of ethics the
distinctions we could make are that in
postmodern that ethics were relativistic
or situational they have situational
ethics what would you do in this
situation instead of as and as a
reaction to this notion that there is a
there is an identifiable and absolute
good answer to this ethical question and
that is been built on an integrative
manner to think of what's authentic so
you're not just lazy they're situational
but how you bought bent it to what is
perhaps a good principle
yourself and in terms of morality the
distinctions we could make is from the
concept that there are discoverable
absolute principles to the notion that
there is the right thing to do which is
starting to incorporate the situation in
this relativistic idea to a move toward
something that we'd be more classified
as spirituality and we can combine these
two words to think of what is happening
now in a postponed modern view is the
kind of search for an authentic
spirituality so those are some of the
distinctions that I think are important
as we look at what is come before how
the postmodern views are in a sense more
dramatically reactionary to the modern
domains and views and that the move from
postmodern to post postmodern is a more
of an integrity or synthetic move and
with that is arising a whole different
world view or view across many different
domains and in the next video we'll look
at the edge of that frontier from even
the integrity to the territory that the
mahjongg course really wants to
voyage to
you